JACK FINN MURRAY

Mobile: (951) 514-8256 ♦ **E-mail**: jackmurray445@gmail.com ♦ **Site**: jackfmurray.me **LinkedIn**: linkedin.com/jn/jackfmurray ♦ **GitHub**: github.com/jackmurray45

Summary

"Highly motivated software engineer who with a diverse skill set and experience in high demand environments. Primary experience with full stack with an emphasis on back-end/middle-tier. Quick with learning new software design concepts and adapting to the constantly changing tech environment while using out of the box thinking for unique problem solving."

Technical Expertise

Software: Python, PHP, C#/C++, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git

Professional Experience

Home Campus

Software Developer, Costa Mesa, CA

June 2018 - Current

- Develop web-based applications used by thousands of athletic departments nationwide for report generating, schedule and roster tracking, and more
- Design and implement APIs used by third parties and build solutions to consume external APIs
- Tech stack includes PHP (Laravel), MySQL, and JavaScript; operating AWS features such as EC2, S3, and RDS to host sites and manage services; configure GitLab CI/CD pipeline for fast, easy deployment
- Collaborate in a team environment to discuss database design, code structure, and code reviews and providing documentation on new features to assist in the learning process for other developers

Home Campus

Software Developer Intern, Costa Mesa, CA

March 2018 - June 2018

- Refactored and built on codebase and parlayed updates in team meetings with executive team
- Assisted developers on major projects and given creative freedom to foster own projects

American Heart Association

Web Developer Intern, Irvine, CA

June 2017 – January 2018

- Created Simple Cooking with Heart website using HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Consulted colleagues with a non-technical background regarding website content and user interface

Relevant Projects

Lara-Post Web Application (github.com/jackmurray45/Lara-Post)

Built full stack message board web application using the Laravel framework. Features in the project include: authentication with middleware, RESTful API that utilizes JWT and allows for CRUD operations, unit and functional testing, Bootstrap for responsive web pages.

Education & Leadership

University of California, Irvine – B.S. Computer Science – 2014-2018

HackUCI - Corporate Outreach Committee

January 2016 - June 2018

- Organizer for the largest hackathon in Orange County with over 450 participants
- Contacted and interacted with numerous companies professionally to form partnerships

Management and Information Student Society - Mentor

June 2016 – June 2018

- Inspired students through giving academic and professional advice
- Adapted teaching styles with mentees to provide a more personal mentorship experience